Guide to the Collection of Type Specimens
Yale University Arts Library
- Manufacturer, Series II
  - Typographers Inc. (Box 6)
    - Typositor faces available at Graphic Arts Typographers, Inc., undated
  - Typographic Art, Inc. (Box 6)
    - Photocomposition and Headline Typeface Booklet, undated
    - Photocomposition Typeface Directory, undated
  - TypoGraphics Communications, Inc. (Box 6)
    - T.J. Lyons Antique Type Collection, undated
    - Portfolio One, undated
    - Portfolio Two, undated
  - Valiquette, Bernard (Box 6)
    - Specimens de Caracteres, undated
  - Village Press (Box 6)
    - A Specimen of Types Designed and Engraved at the Village Press, 1932
  - Visi-Graphics (Box 6)
    - C-B-F Border System The Creative Edge, undated
  - Visual Graphics Corp. (Box 6)
    - Fifteen Award Winning Type Face Designs, undated
  - Volk (Box 7)
    - A Sentimental Journey Through a Typographic Jungle, undated
    - Overlay-Guide, undated
    - Borders Initials Special Rules, undated
    - Linewtype Specimens, undated
    - Volk Types, undated; 3
    - Another Showing of New Specimens for your Kurt H. Volk, Inc. Type Book, undated; 4
    - This Packet Contains Specimen Pages for your Kurt H. Volk, Inc. Type Book, undated; 4
    - Form, undated
  - Wagner (Ludwig Wagner Aktien-Gesellschaft) (Box 7)
    - Silhouette 40, undated
  - Walden, Sons and Mott, Inc. (Box 7)
    - Type Face Directory, 1941
  - Waverly Press (Box 7)
    - Type, undated
  - Westcott and Thomson Inc. (Box 7)
    - The Favored Fifty, undated
    - Photofaces, undated
    - A to Z in Graphic Arts, undated
    - A List of Types, undated
    - Some English Monotype Faces, undated; 3 copies
    - The Big 4, undated
    - Centaur, undated
    - Type Faces, undated
  - Westvaco / Westvirginia Pulp and Paper (Box 7)
    - Typographic Quest, undated
    - Display Types, undated
    - A Typographic Quest Number Three, undated
    - A Typographic Quest Number Four, undated
    - A Typographic Quest Number Five, undated
    - A Typographic Quest Number Six, undated
  - Wrightson, Inc. (Box 7)
    - Types up to 144 point, undated
  - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Blackletter, undated
- Typographer, Series III
  This series is arranged alphabetically, usually by the typographer's surname.
  - Adams, Ansel (Box 7)
  - Adler, Elmer (Box 7)
  - Anderson, Gregg (Box 7)
  - Angelo, Valenti (Box 7)
  - Anthoensen, Fred (Box 7)
  - Armstrong, Margaret (Box 7)
  - Audubon, J.W. (Box 7)
  - Bainton, Roland (Box 7)
  - Barancik, Robert (Box 7)
  - Barnett, Jim (Box 7)
  - Baskerville, John (Box 7)
  - Baskin, Leonard (Box 7)
  - Bauer Type Founding (Box 7)
  - Behreus, Roy R (Box 7)
  - Bennett, Paul (Box 7)
  - Benson, John Howard (Box 7)
  - Benson, Richard (Box 7)
  - Harold Berliner's Typefoundry (Box 7)
  - Bernhard, Lucian (Box 7)
  - Bradley, Will (Box 7)
  - Buhler, Curt F. (Box 7)
  - Buell, Abel (Box 10)
  - Burgess, Molly (Box 7)
  - Burgess, Starling (Box 7)
  - Burrett, Edward (Box 7)
  - Carnes, A Burton (Box 7)
  - Cary, Melbert (Box 7)
  - Caxton, William (Box 7)
  - Chapell, Warren (Box 7)
  - Cleland, T.M. (Box 10)
  - Cockerell, S. C. (Box 7)
  - College Press (Box 10)
  - Cundall, Joseph (Box 7)
  - Da Boll, Raymond (Box 7)
  - Dair, Carl (Box 7)
  - DaRif, Andrea (Box 7)
  - De Vinne (Box 7)
  - Dibdin, Thomas Frognall (Box 7)
  - Dickman, Alfred (Box 7)
  - Dreyfus, John (Box 7)
  - Dwiggens, William Addison (Box 7)
  - Eichenberg, Toni (Box 10)
  - Ellis, Richard Williamson (Box 7)
  - Emmons, Earl H. (Box 7)
  - Everson, William (Box 7)
  - Farrier, Herbert (Box 7)
  - Fournier, Pierre Simone (Box 7)
  - Fraktur (Box 7)
  - Fredericks, Claude (Box 7)
  - Fredericks, Claude (Box 10)
  - Frutiger, Adrien (Box 7)
  - Fukuda, Shigeo (Box 7)
  - Fukuda, Shigeo (Box 10)
  - Gemming, Klaus (Box 7)
  - Gill, Eric (Box 7)
  - Godard, Keith (Box 7)
  - Goines, David Lance (Box 7)
  - Goudy, Frederic William (Box 7)
  - Grabhorn, Edwin and Robert (Box 7)
  - Granjon, Robert (Box 7)
  - Grear, Malcolm (Box 7)
  - Gutenberg, Johann (Box 7)
  - Haas, Robert (Box 8)
  - Hagar, William (Box 8)
  - Hammer, Victor (Box 8)
  - Harter, Evelyn (Box 8)
  - Harvard, Steven (Box 8)
  - Harvard, Steven (Box 8)
  - Harvey, Michael (Box 8)
  - Hebrew Monotype Press (Box 8)
  - Herrick, George (Box 8)
  - Hofer, Philip (Box 8)
  - Hoover, Roland (Box 8)
  - Hornby, St. John (Box 8)
  - Hunter, Dard (Box 8)
  - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery (Box 8)
  - Jaffe, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Johnson, John (Box 8)
  - Johnston, Edward (Box 8)
  - Kent, Rockwell (Box 8)
  - Lawton, Kennedy (Box 8)
  - Lehrer, Warren (Box 8)
  - Leslie, Robert L. (Box 8)
  - Levrant de Bretteville, Sheila (Box 8)
  - Loewy, Raymond (Box 8)
  - Londenberg, Kurt (Box 8)
  - Mackie, George (Box 8)
  - Manutius, Aldus (Box 8)
  - Mayakovsky (Box 8)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas C. (Box 8)
  - Mardersteig, Giovanni (Box 8)
  - Merker, K. K. (Box 8)
  - Middleton, Robert H. (Box 8)
  - Miers, Earl Schenck (Box 8)
  - Morris, William (Box 8)
  - Morris, William (Box 10)
  - Morison, Stanley (Box 8)
  - Moser, Barry (Box 8)
  - Mosley, James (Box 8)
  - Nash, Ray (Box 8)
  - Nesbit, Alexander (Box 8)
  - Offner, Elliot (Box 8)
  - Porter, Ben (Box 8)
  - Prang, L (Box 8)
  - Ransom, Harry Hunt (Box 8)
  - Rand, Paul (Box 8)
  - Reed, Philip (Box 8)
  - Ward, Ritchie (Box 8)
  - Rogers, Bruce (Box 8)
  - Rogers, Bruce (Box 8)
  - Rudge, William Edwin (Box 8)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph (Box 8)
  - Saunders and Otley (Box 8)
  - Schaedler (John N. Schaedler, Inc) (Box 8)
  - Schiller, Albert (Box 8)
  - Schiller, Al (Box 8)
  - Schiller, Al (Box 10)
  - Sikorski, T. (Box 8)
  - Silver, Rollo (Box 8)
  - Silver, Rollo (Box 10)
  - Sims, Valentine (Box 8)
  - Sizer, Theodore (Box 8)
  - Smith, Charles (Box 8)
  - Standard, Paul (Box 8)
  - Stone, Reynolds (Box 8)
  - Taylor, Robert (Box 8)
  - Thomajan, P.K. (Box 8)
  - Tiessen, Wolfgang (Box 8)
  - Tschichold, Jan (Box 8)
  - Tufte, Edward (Box 8)
  - Twyman, Michael (Box 8)
  - Updike, D.B. (Box 8)
  - Van Krimpen, Jan (Box 8)
  - Van Vechten, George W. (Box 8)
  - Verlag, Herbert, Reichner (Box 8)
  - Walker, Emery (Box 8)
  - Warde, Beatrice (Box 8)
  - Weiler, Joseph (Box 8)
  - Weil, James L. (Box 8)
  - Whitehill, W. W. (Box 8)
  - Wiebking, Robert (Box 8)
  - Wilson, Adrian (Box 8)
  - Wolpe, Berthold (Box 8)
  - Wroth, Lawrence (Box 8)
  - Zapf, Hermann and Gudrun (Box 8)
  - Zwart, Piet (Box 8)
- Broadsides, Series IV
  This series is divided into four subseries: Typeface; Manufacturer; Typographer; and Calligraphy and Lettering. Items within each subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  - Typeface (Box 11)
    - Baskerville, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Bell, Monotype Corporation Ltd., undated
    - Caslon, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Centaur, Eastern Corporation, 1948
    - Centaur, Mackenzie and Harris, Inc., 1948; 3 copies
    - Centaur and Arrighi, Mackenzie & Harris, Inc., 1948
      See Broadside Drawer 1.6.
    - Cheltenham, Eastern Corporation, 1948; 2 copies
    - Cloister Black, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Fairfield, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Fraktura, Imperial Presse Des Berlags, 1992
    - Futura, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Garamond Bold, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Gothic Alternate and Franklin, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Goudy Old Style, Eastern Corporation, 1948 undated
    - Goudy "Lost" Types, Eastern Corporation, undated; 2 copies
    - Janson, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Lutetia, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - Monotype, Lanston Monotype machine Company, undated
    - Perpetua- Monotype, Eastern Corporation, undated; 2 copies
    - Saskia – Jan Tshicold's typeface by Chuck Routhier, uppercase only., undated
    - Square-Serif, Eastern Corporation, undated
    - The Times New Roman, Mackenzie and Harris, Inc., 1960
    - The Times New Roman and italic, Mackenzie and Harris, Inc., 1960
    - Unidentified, undated; 4
    - Weiss, Eastern Corporation, undated
  - Manufacturer (Box 11)
    - Bibliographical Press Yale University: untitled, 1999
    - Eastern Corporation: A Specimen of Types Originally Cast in Philadelphia by Binny and Ronaldson; This is a Specimen Sheet of Grayda Type Augmented by Barnum; This is a Specimen Sheet of Old-Fashioned Types, undated
    - Monotype Corporation: A Comparison of Typefaces, undated
    - Morgan Press: Wood Types, undated
    - Oxford Press: Oriental and Other Types, undated
  - Typographer (Box 11)
    - Caslon, William, undated; 4
    - Goudy, Frederic W., undated; 3
    - Van Dijck, Christoffel, undated; 2
  - Calligraphy and Lettering (Box 11)
    - This is a Specimen Sheet of Calligraphy: Disciplined Freedom is the Essence of it, undated
    - A Showing of Job, undated; 3
    - A Development and Lineage Theory for the Roman Alphabet, undated; 2
    - Modern Lettering and Poster Design Lessons 2-6 (5), undated; 5
      Scope and Contents
      Includes: The Engraver's Guide; The Sign Painter's Manual; The School Masters Assistant; and the Young Student's Desideratum.
- Miscellaneous, Series V
  Miscellaneous materials related to typography, including Graphic Arts subject files with both primary and secondary resources.
  - Typography (Box 12)
  - Typography – Examples, Title Pages (Box 12)
  - Typographic Oddities (Box 12)
  - Type Design (Box 12)
  - Type Founding (Box 12)
  - Type Cases (Box 12)
  - Typefaces (Box 12)
  - Type Specimens (Box 12)
  - Type – Baskerville (Box 12)
  - Type – Bell (Box 12)
  - Type – Bembo (Box 12)
  - Type – Bodoni (Box 12)
  - Type – Borders and Flowers (Box 12)
  - Type – Bulmer (Box 12)
  - Type – Caslon (Box 12)
  - Type – Centaur + Arrighi (Box 12)
  - Type – Cheltenham (Box 12)
  - Type – De Vinne (Box 12)
  - Type – Electra (Box 12)
  - Type – Elzevir (Box 12)
  - Type – Estienne (Box 12)
  - Type – Finn (Box 12)
  - Type – Galliard (Box 12)
  - Type – Garamond (Box 12)
  - Type – Granjon (Box 12)
  - Type – Greek (Box 12)
  - Type – Janson (Box 12)
  - Type – Jenson (Box 12)
  - Type – Lutetia (Box 12)
  - Type – Montaigne (Box 12)
  - Type – Old Church Slavonic (Box 12)
  - Type – Open Kapitalen (Box 12)
  - Type – Perpetua (Box 12)
  - Type – Society Text (Box 12)
  - Type – Stone (Box 12)
  - Type – Uncial (Box 12)
  - Type – Wood (Box 12)